Nitin Savant

Software Engineer | Minneapolis, MN nitinsavant@gmail.com | nitinsavant.com

PROFILE

Software Engineer with 5+ years experience in software implementation, systems administration, and project management. I have several years of experience building applications and enjoy tackling challenging problems such as designing data structures for distributed systems.

EXPERIENCE

Conclave, Co-Creator / Software Engineer

Oct 2017 - Jan 2017

- Co-created a real-time, collaborative text editor from scratch in JavaScript
- Built a custom conflict-free replicated data type (CRDT) to resolve conflicts between users; handles 100k operations in less than 1 sec
- Created a peer-to-peer architecture using WebRTC
- Scaled P2P architecture to support dozens of concurrent users
- Presented at Node, Ruby, and JavaScript meetups in Minneapolis

Foodiker, Technical Co-Founder

Mar 2016 - Sep 2016

- Developed company focused on food sustainability
- Designed and developed Rails website at foodiker.com

Laserfiche, Solutions Engineer / Program Manager Jul 2010 - Mar 2015

- Implemented document management solutions across higher education, government, and financial sectors
- Configured and troubleshooted Windows Server, SQL Server, and IIS environments
- Promoted to manage program of 30+ concurrent projects staffed among 15 engineers, specifically resolving escalated issues related to resources, budget, timeline, and client satisfaction
- Designed tools resulting in elimination of program assistant role, including web-based project status report and staffing tool that enabled the prediction of project start dates

EDUCATION

Arizona State University, M.S. in Electrical Engineering, 2010 Harvey Mudd College, B.S. in Engineering, 2008

• Men's Basketball — 2004-2008

SKILLS

Ruby, JavaScript, Node.js, Rails, SQL, Go (novice)